<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Federico Simonetta</title>
    <link>https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Federico Simonetta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Art and similar stuffs</title>
      <link>https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/art/</guid>
      <description>Il prodotto artistico Definire il concetto di arte in generale, non è semplice. Le persone parlano di arte per riferirsi genericamente a un processo intellettuale e materiale che produce un bene fruibile, materiale o meno; affinché tale bene venga definito arte, deve possedere alcune caratteristiche che variano in base al contesto culturale. Potrei quindi analizzare tali svariate caratteristiche per poi scoprire, però, che la mia stessa analisi sarebbe soggetta al mio contesto culturale e che pertanto non sarebbe comunque universalmente valida.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contradictions</title>
      <link>https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/contradictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/contradictions/</guid>
      <description>Human beings in 21th century has to live with a new incredible discovery: our world perception is contradictory.
Here, I will try to list all the contradictions that humans have to face. The ratio for which they are listed here is that it may be impossible to solve these contradictions without stopping being a human, that is without stopping perceiving ourself as an active coscience.
Categories only exist in in our mind, but our mind also tells us that categories do not exist Humans perceive a push towards something but they cannot understand why nor what </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantastic notes</title>
      <link>https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/fantastic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/fantastic/</guid>
      <description>Categories We organize what we perceive in the world in categories. Everywhere we find categories: words, concepts, objects. But why we do so? Are categories really part of the intrinsic essence of where we live? In a certain sense, we could say that the needing for categories comes from the perception of the world as a set of multiple different objects.
It is completely instictual finding differences between a chair and a glass, or between a table and a laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L&#39;effetto dell&#39;informatica `user centered`</title>
      <link>https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/user_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/user_center/</guid>
      <description>Ipertrofia segnica La società del Novecento è stata caratterizzata da un sovraffollamento di segnali. Ovunque andiamo, troviamo segni, indicazioni, scritte, simboli. Viviamo in un horror vacui della comunicazione. La società degli anni duemila è andata oltre. Nel XX sec. il capitalismo cominciò a martellare le persone con informazioni le più disparate con l&amp;rsquo;obiettivo di: sostenere i consumi, garantire la comprensione delle leggi e indicare il comportamento a cui le persone dovevano attenersi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of Notes</title>
      <link>https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/allnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federicosimonetta.eu.org/notes/allnotes/</guid>
      <description>This a list of personal notes about various stuffs. Be careful, because you could get crazy (or maybe you could just think that I&amp;rsquo;m crazy, which is probably part of the truth).
Fantastic notes Effetti sociali dell&amp;rsquo;informatica user-centered Assurda filosofia dell&amp;rsquo;arte Contrdictions </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
