<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Remote on Federico Simonetta</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/remote/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Remote on Federico Simonetta</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>english</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 09:14:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/remote/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Una semplice introduzione a Git</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/git_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 09:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/git_intro/</guid>
      <description>L&amp;rsquo;idea di git è di salvare varie versioni apportate ai file in un repository.&#xA;Le modifiche apportate si salvano sottoforma di commit. Ogni commit contiene le nuove versioni dei file modificati che si vogliono salvare. Idealmente, ogni commit dovrebbe rispettare il principio di singola responsabilità: dovrebbe cioè riguardare una sola funzionalità o caratteristica del software. Ogni commit porta con se un messaggio che descrive brevemente cosa è stato modificato, un timestamp non modificabile e un hash che consente di identificarlo univocamente.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Last Resort - how to force remote reboot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the_last_resort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 11:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the_last_resort/</guid>
      <description>Problem Deadlocks are bad creatures in the unix world. Sometimes, you willl need to kill your machine forcely, but what if you are using a remote machine?&#xA;In the COVID-19 situation, it could be difficult to get a machine up again if you forcely shutdown it (e.g. shutdown -now). So, you need to reboot. The issue is that reboot kindly unmount filesystems and wait for processes to shutdown.&#xA;Solution If you want to abruptly shutdown your system, simply does as following:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing and testing on a remote host</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/remote_editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 11:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/remote_editing/</guid>
      <description>Workflow In this document, you can find an introduction to tools commonly used for remote editing and development. The generla workflow is the following:&#xA;You create and edit code on your local machine An indipendent software mirrors your code to the host (syncthing in this document) You interface with the host through terminal, give commands and run code (tmux) Finally, you debug your code (debug section), and edit it your local machine This workflow allows you to:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
